I love football. I love almost
everything about football. There's one
thing I don't like and that is the
sexism. Like obviously that's a little
bit difficult. Um because there's still
a certain type of bloke that seems to
think that um like I can't know as much
about football as he can, right? It's
like he doesn't think I've got time to
both watch Match of the Day and buy
sanitary products.
But the key thing about that is you
stockpile in the summer.
See you ready for when the season starts
in the winter.
>> [applause]
>> I love these guys though. I call them
the proper footballing geysers. Uh
you've probably seen them knocking
around. They're they're big guys,
massive [\h__\h] heads. Uh big thick neck
veins where they store all of their
repressed emotions.
Weirdly, they're always very active on
Twitter for some reason. And they'll
always have a Twitter handle which is
like @ milwallmike69.
And then you'll click onto their Twitter
profile and their bio will always say
something like, "Love my kids, hate
nonses.
You're sort of thinking, "Come on, Mike.
Pick a side."
[applause]
I love these guys though cuz um they've
uh they've recently found me on social
media and what they love doing is they
love doing sassy little snarky comments
underneath my standup videos and um they
do these sort of sick burns and there's
there's a phrase that I've sort of
started noticing recently that they're
all using. So, what they've all said
under my standup videos is this phrase.
They say, "Luis Kapowi looks like he's
let himself go."
Which pisses me off cuz Luis Kapow's
already let himself go.
I feel what they're trying to do by
comparing me to a plus-sized man is to
imply that I'm ugly. It doesn't bother
me as an insult. Honestly, doesn't
bother me as an insult. I know that I'm
ugly. Not in a self-deprecating way. Um,
just in the way that all British people
are ugly.
Do you know this? You are absolutely
vile. I'm sorry if you don't know this.
You're absolutely vile. Okay? And I I
didn't know this until recently when I
started traveling outside of the UK in
the last couple of years. Um, everything
they say about us is true. Okay? But
it's not your fault. The reason that
we're ugly is because um, and I'm
specifically talking about white British
people here. I don't want to draw anyone
else into our ugly mess.
The reason that we're ugly is because
back in the day, the Vikings came over,
stole all of our hot women, took them
back to mainland Europe, which is why
everyone in Sweden is smoking hot, and
we look like someone put a wig on some
Billy Bear ham.
[applause] But it had an amazing it had
an amazing reaction because it meant
that we had to develop great
personalities because you never heard
someone go, "This is my Swedish friend.
He's a laugh.
So, I would say that I'm British hot,
which is ugly but a hoot.
So, I I love football, as I say. Um, and
I kind of get these bloss that that are
a bit toxic cuz football makes me toxic,
too. I do worry about my toxicity,
though. Like, I don't let I've got a
girlfriend now, and I don't let her
watch me watch the football because it
almost she saw me watch the football
once, it almost ruined our relationship
before it had even started. So what
happened was she came into the living
room. She said to me, "Chloe, why are
you laughing?" And I had to explain that
Chelsea had just gone 32 down and the
camera had panned to a crying child.
I hated teaching and it's a brilliant,
wonderful, noble profession, obviously
teaching. I hated it cuz I didn't want
to do it. The only thing that got me
through those years were children
because some of you parents will know
children are wonderful and
weird.
I used to teach a class in North London.
You'll think I'm exaggerating this. I'm
not. This is just one class I'm talking
about. They were the strangest group of
human beings I have ever seen assembled
in one place. Right? They were the
strangest group of human beings ever in
one. And I include all of the series of
Big Brother in that. Right, I'll talk
you through some of them. There was a
child called Marwood in that class,
which isn't a real name, let's be
honest. He was absolutely on a different
planet to the rest of us. I'll prove it.
I once said to him, "Marwood, what are
you going to do when you leave school?"
Straight away, he said, "Well, I'm going
to be one of two things, sir. I'm going
to be a gynecologist or a train driver."
I said, "They're rather contrasting
professions, Marwood. This is only funny
if you believe me." Wasn't trying to be
funny at this point. He went, "Yeah,
yeah, they are, aren't they, sir?" I
suppose at the end of the day, I just
like tunnels.
Fortunately, there was a child in that
class that made up for all of them. Her
name was Karen Pal. She was my favorite
student of all time. She was 11 years of
age, this big, and had two fascinating
characteristics. Number one, her
internal compass was buggered, right?
So, she was 10 minutes late to every
single lesson, and the school wasn't
that big. 10 minutes late. The second
was even though she was 11, she spoke
for reasons best known to our creator
like an repressed 1940s housewife.
And you think if I'm exaggerating this,
I am not exaggerating it. She would come
into my class like this. Hello, sir. How
are you today?
I say, I'm fine, thanks. Karen, how are
you? SHE GOES, YES, I'M VERY WELL,
THANKS.
I must SAY, I'M VERY MUCH LOOKING
FORWARD TO TODAY'S IMPROVISATION.
I'll give you an example of her compass.
[laughter]
She came to see me after a lesson. This
is more verbatim quote. She went,
"Excuse me, sir. Can I have a word with
you, please?" "Well, of course you can,
Car. What's the problem?" She goes, "I
just wanted to say that I thought my
performance in your lesson today was a
little below par."
I said, "Really? I thought you were
great." "No, no. I thought my use of
characterization was paper thin. Thought
the way I moved around the space was
appalling. And my group work was
something to be condemned. Then I would
like to offer you my most humble of
apologies.
I said, "You listen to me, Karen Pal.
You never need to apologize to me. You
are my favorite pupil because you make
me laugh my head off."
Now go outside and enjoy your lunchtime.
You've deserved it. She said, "You know
what? I think I will."
[laughter]
I turned round at that point to do a
little bit of admin. Ladies and
gentlemen, Karen was then faced with a
choice.
She could leave my room via the only
exit
or she could go into my costume
cupboard.
I don't know what happened, but for
safety, I'll tell you this. I locked my
costume cupboard before I went for my
lunch. Then I went away for a whole
hour. When I came back, I opened the
cupboard and I swear to you, that child
was standing with her back to me in a
scene from the Diddy Man remake of the
Blair Witch Project
doing this.
AND I WENT, COURAGE, SHE WENT, "HELLO,
SIR."
I SAID, "HAVE YOU BEEN IN THERE FOR A
WHOLE HOUR?" SHE SAID, "I'M RATHER
AFRAID I HAVE."
I said, "OH MY GOD, I AM SO SORRY." SHE
SAID, "DON'T you apologize to me. I'VE
ONLY GOT MYSELF TO BLAME. I'LL SEE YOU
LATER.
[applause]
>> But here's the thing about being married
a very long time. You get to know each
other so well, right? I mean, my husband
knows me well. I know my husband so well
at this point that we can have a
full-blown argument from start to finish
and he's not even home,
you know. So, this year I have been
married 21 years.
Thank you. Thank you. Um I know it looks
like I could have been a child bride,
which where I'm from, totally possible.
Anyway, I wasn't a child bride. Anyway,
so uh 21 years. And here's what I've
learned in 21 years. That to stay
married and stay happy, because it's not
naturally the same thing. To stay
married and stay happy, what you must do
is keep your focus on what is important.
Keep your focus on what is important.
Let everything else fall away. See, I'll
explain. The other day, my husband and I
were having an argument. A face tof face
one. The one where he's actually at
home. Um, so we're having an argument
and uh, well, I mean, I say argument.
The fact is after 21 years, my husband
and I don't really have arguments. We
have throwdowns.
You know, throwdown like MMA level.
Do you know what MMA is, sir? Yeah.
marriage martial arts proper matter what
the topic my husband and I both always
bring it for everything because we know
that after 21 years and three kids
nobody's [\h__\h] going anywhere
right we are just trying to get to the
end of this somehow
and also you should know like I told you
when I arrived here I got a UK passport
my husband is Scandinavian. He didn't
bother. And then we were having this
argument and he was like, "I don't
understand why you didn't do it this
way." And I said, "Really? What I don't
understand is why you don't [\h__\h] off
back where you came from."
[applause]
Apollo, I cannot lie to you. It felt
pretty good.
Oh my god, what a great phrase. I am
totally on board with it now. Knock
yourselves out.
Such a good feeling it gives you
afterwards, you know. Um the problem was
it bothered our children a little bit
because we were having lunch. It was
Sunday. Um our youngest child, she said,
"Oh no, mama said the f-word." And I
said, "Oh, darling, you're right. I did.
But you know what? When you grow up and
meet the man of your dreams, so will
you."
And then my teenage son said something.
But let me explain, ladies and
gentlemen. Between 45 to 85% of what
this child says, I don't understand.
Because he's a teenager. He just looked
at me and said, "Why so salty, bro?"
And then our middle child, apart from
being somewhat fractured, she's also
very woke.
by which I mean she doesn't understand
the difference between racism and a joke
about racism.
So she got very upset and she said, "You
can't say that to dad. That's racist." I
said, "Racist? Look at my face.
I can't be racist. Everybody knows only
white people are racist."
Oh, she got angry. Ah, she stomped out
of the room. And I was like, "Oh, come
on, darling. Sorry. It was a joke. I
know you're half white. Oops.
I started learning French really young
at the age of eight or something in
primary school and our French teacher to
help it sink in our brains used to play
little games with us and one of the
games was that we had to draw a name out
of the hat and that would be our French
name for the rest of term. Yeah. So I
withdrew Marcel and she taught me that
if anyone ever asked the question toel
my response should be jimmael Marcel.
Right now, I got all the way to degree
level and two trips to Paris with that
knowledge and no one ever corrected me.
And I went in on me first day of the
lecture and the professor goes, "Ah,
bonjour. Uh, come on to tapel." I
thought, "Well, this is going to be very
easy course." I went, "Bonjour, Jimel
Marcel." He's like, "No, no, come on to
tapel." And I went, "Jimel Marcel." He's
like, "No, no, come on to tapel." And I
went, "Jimel Marcel." He's like, "No,
come on to tapel." I went, "Jimel
Marcel." He's like, "No, no, come on."
Martel, he's like, "No, no, come on."
He's like, "No, no,
Martel." He's like, "No, no, come on to
Tapel." And I went, "What is wrong with
you? You said you were French."
I went, "Jim
Marel." He's like, "No, come on to
Tapel. What is your name?" I was like,
"Jimapel Marcel, my name is Steven." Um,
[applause] so educated
and as part of our course, yeah, we had
to do a year abroad. Hold on. Um, gapy.
Gapa. Um,
we did, Jimmy. We had to do a year
abroad, right? So, I moved to the south
of France for a year. And I'm dating
myself with this reference. I do know.
But um I thought it would be like a
Hillary Duff film, right? Do you know
where I'd like move to the south of
France, get a job in a little booerie,
fall in love, move into the guy's chat,
and never have to come and perform in
Hammersmith. Do you know what I mean?
And me and me friends all had a bit of a
dream. Like me friend Kate, she's
married to a guy now called Flon and
lives in Nice. That was my dream, [\h__\h]
My friend Sam got with a guy while we
were there and his name was Nicola. And
I even got with a guy while we're there
for one term and his name was Kevin.
It wasn't even Cavine.
I went all the [laughter] way to the
south of France and found the only guy
from Stockport.
Just call me Sally Webster.
And the thing I hated the most about
doing that year abroad was I don't like
flying. Give me a tip if you like
flying.
>> Give me a tip if you don't like it.
Yeah. All the ones sat in the sky.
I really hate it. Yeah. Because
everyone's like it's the safest form of
transport, but that's not true, is it?
Because um speak to someone that's been
in a crash and
that is valid. That is really valid. And
I've had to find me way of getting round
it. You need hints, tricks, don't you?
So me therapist said, "You just need to
sit on the plane doing this.
I get thrown off the plane if I do that,
Julie. And the way I've been trying to
get around it, hear me out, you're going
to think I'm mad, right? Do you know
sometimes when you look at someone and
you think like Aaron, I look at you and
I go, you would never die in a plane
crash. You've got that kind of face, you
know? It's like, you're not going to go
that way. Whereas some people, they've
got that face where it's like, have you
already been in one? Um,
and I flew to Dublin this year and it
was the best flight I'd ever had, right?
Because I found someone like you, Aaron.
I found some Peter Barlow from
Coronation Street was on the flight and
I thought, Peter Barlow is not going to
die in a Ryionaire flight.
He's already been through too much.
Do you remember years ago when they were
making Braveheart,
everyone said, "Oh, it's ridiculous.
Mel Gibson playing a Scottish guy.
That's not going to be very convincing."
And look at him now. An alcoholic
racist.
The most Scottish thing I've ever seen.
I was going through a town called
Bathgate at night and there was a guy
pissing against a front door
like that
who then took out his keys and went
inside.
I'm from Glasgow. If I had to explain
Glasgow to you, I'd say that if I had to
pick a city in the world where I could
depend on a member of the public to
punch a man who was on fire,
TO PUNCH A FLAMING MAN TO THE GROUND.
WE SHOULD get a photo of that blown up
and use it as the welcome sign at
Scottish airports.
And underneath we should have the words,
"Scotland welcomes careful drivers."
I mean, the naivity of al-Qaeda trying
to bring religious war to Glasgow.
We're 400 YEARS AHEAD OF YOU GUYS.
[laughter] You've not even got a
football team.
There's a fallacy, isn't there, that
that baggage handler prevented hundreds
of people from being horribly burned.
These were Scottish people flying to
Spain.
[applause]
People say it's good they didn't hit a
fuel depot. I think it's good they
didn't hit the queue coming out of duty
free.
They're going up like Hiroshima.
British army have got a big recruiting
drive on in Scotland at the minute cuz
that's what you need if you're fighting
an unwinable war in the desert. More
ginger people.
That's why they couldn't send Prince
Harry. They couldn't afford the
resources required to start developing
factor 60,000 sunblock.
It's not always the friendliest place in
the world, Scotland. I once saw an
English guy in Glasgow trying to order a
pint of lagger and lime and the barman
went, "We don't do cocktails.
We can't just be d negative bastards up
there." John Loi Bird invented the TV
and when people came up to congratulate
him, they went, "Ah, but there's [\h__\h]
all on."
We're looking forward to the Olympics in
London.
>> I'll take that as a no.
They say the Olympics is going to
rekindle English national pride. I mean,
come on. For 9.2 2 billion. You could
have written [\h__\h] off Germany onto the
moon.
>> We're here to talk about relationships.
Let's let's crack straight on with the
first slide.
Making Don't No, don't laugh at that.
That's not That's not meant to be funny.
Please, let's let's not have another
folks on our hands, please.
Making divorce work. Now, given that it
is a rocky ride, an emotional roller
coaster, I start off with a joke, ladies
and gentlemen, just to loosen us up.
Here it is. If you're going to get
divorced, you have to be like the man in
the toll booth. Why is that, Keith?
Well, you have to be willing to accept,
this is the joke,
change.
It's a zinger. It's a zinger. When you
divorce, there is sweeping change.
changes right across your life in every
area. One of the first things to change
is the locks. You may don't please don't
laugh at that, please. You please you
may come home one day and find that your
key no longer fits your wife's lock.
Another man's key is fitting your wife's
lock. And stop that. STOP IT. STOP
stamping on that. Riaz with a zed.
Please stop it. It's it's not that sort
of a show. Well, I mean, it's not a
show, is it? It's it's a talk, but it's
not smuting. So, you may come home and
find that your key no longer fits the
lock.
Good.
Yes, it can. And it can be very
difficult to tell why a relationship is
going to go wrong. Why is that? Well, I
think it's because at the beginning of
any relationship when two people get
together, there's always a sense of of
what? Hammer Smith, at the beginning of
a relationship, a sense of
>> pardon?
>> Worry. No.
>> Anyone else? At the beginning of a
relationship, a sense of
>> forboding. Forboding is the wrong
answer.
Lust. Lust. No. No. No. uncertainty.
There's always a sense of uncertainty, a
feeling of will they,
>> won't they, and there's no way of
Please, Hammer Smith, take it seriously.
We're talking about emotions,
a sense of will they, won't they, and
there's no Hammersmith, I will walk off
the stage, please.
There's no way of predicting when a
couple get together whether or not the
relationship will work. Will it last a
long time? No.
Not a chance in hell.
Will they stick together?
No. No.
Will the marriage endure?
Yes.
Lee and Leslie. Now, Lee and Leslie are
a lesson to us all. They've made a
marriage work. So, why is it then that
when they can make a marriage work, so
many others can't?
Paul Simon said, "There are 50 ways to
leave your lover."
One,
Smith, time out. Please start to take it
seriously.
One, slip out the back jack.
Two, make a new plan. Stan
and 48 others. I was in France a couple
of years ago. Had to stop to use a lure
at a little service station by the road.
I knew it wasn't going to be a fivestar
experience. From the moment I walked in
there, the lady in the kiosk was eating
a pig's trotter with the one remaining
tooth.
Watching a chipmunk try to eat a piece
of corn on the cob.
I approached her and of course as a
proud remainer I said to her in my best
French
she went it's round the back it is round
the back so I went round the back and
there it was a little shed of we go and
I opened the Go. VOILA.
SQUIRTY.
Throw up France. Anyway, there was
nowhere else to go. So, I had to go in.
I had to use it. I had to use it. So, I
went in and I closed the door and it was
brilliant because somebody had attached
a rope to the back of the door. So, you
could essentially absale down into the
squatting
I mean, that is a center parks activity
right there, isn't it?
You'd pay for that. Bungee dump.
Brilliant.
I did notice I was getting a little bit
more nervous as a traveler um on recent
flights I've taken. In your 20ies, you
don't care, do you? Like that. I'll live
forever. I'll live forever. me, I'm
going to live forever. As you get older,
you start to really pay attention to the
uh to the safety announcements on place.
It becomes more urgent. You're more
aware of your own mortality. You know,
they'll start the announcement. I will
definitely pay attention. Absolutely.
Pay attention. The glasses go on, the
headphones come off, book goes down,
notebook comes up.
Last flight I was on, it got to that
point, we've all heard it a thousand
times. We've all heard it a thousand
times. put the little life jacket on,
right? He put the little life jacket on
and she went, she said, "Uh, and of
course, in the event of landing on
water, there is a whistle
to attract attention.
In the event of landing on water, there
is a whistle.
A whistle
to attract attention." Now I think for
the first time in my life I really took
in that whistle,
the fabric of that whistle, if you will,
the the being of that whistle, the
ergonomics of that whistle. There is a
whistle
to attract attention. My brain had the
very helpful thought. It thought, well,
if we have landed on water,
we have essentially fallen out of the
sky from 30 to 40,000 ft in a not
insignificant metal tube that may or may
not be on fire.
If that hasn't attracted attention,
if everybody in the surrounding area has
managed not to notice
[laughter]
and you are then reliant on
I got this
[clears throat]
So, I came to Britain in the early 80s.
We were refugees long before it became
fashionable.
But my favorite immigrants are Polish
people because they properly confused
old-fashioned racists. Have you seen
them? They don't know what to do. What
do we do? What do we say? They're
immigrants, but they're white.
I heard this one bloke go, "Bloody Poles
coming over here with their work ethic."
Which isn't very politically correct.
And And I am I try so hard to be
politically correct. Sometimes I take it
too far. I was at a party recently and I
said to my friend, "Have you met Steve?"
He's a really nice guy. My friend goes,
"Which one's Steve?" Steve was the only
black guy in the room. I found myself
going, "Steve, yeah, is over there. He's
got blue jeans on.
a gray t-shirt, sort of curly hair, and
a Nigerian accent.
And once I was performing at comedy
club, and there was two black guys in
the front row like like you two, but um
but but men and black. Um
you are a man, sir. I'm sorry. It's the
lights. And I said to them, "So, how do
you two know each other?" And they
looked at each other and went, "We
don't."
might as well have had NF tattooed on my
forehead.
I didn't. It was felt tip.
I like friendly. A little bit of
friendly racism is nice. When I was a
little girl, I used to always go to my
friend Katie's house and every time her
dad opened the door, HE'D GO, "HELLO,
SHAPPY. You've been on holiday."
So, um, I have a little boy. I have a
baby boy. I'm a mom. And I'm looking at
you, some of you so young. I could be
your mommy if I lived somewhere rural.
Like a lot of women, I got to my 30s and
I thought, I've got to have a baby now
while my mom's still young enough to
look after it for me.
And I went to all the antiatal classes
and and this woman came up to me, one of
the other moms goes, "Oh, how are you
planning on losing your baby weight?" I
was like, "Well, I was just thinking of
having the child."
And she was like, "Oh, I'm going to be a
yummy mummy. I'm going to lose all yummy
mummy." That's just like a middle- class
way of saying milk.
I was so happy when when I found out
that that I was pregnant. And we we had
a scan and we knew that it was a boy.
And people said to me, "Why did you find
out the sex of your baby? Didn't you
want a surprise?" Well, it's going to be
a boy or a girl. Do you know what I
mean? The only surprise would have been
if it was a puppy.
And there are there are no puppies in my
family.
There's one goat. It's it's it's not a
blood relation.
Thank goodness I have a child. It was no
fun being a broody Iranian woman. Every
time I said to people, "My body thoughts
ticking." They'd hit the ground.
[applause]
[applause] So, with all that going on,
when I did find out I was pregnant, I
was so delighted. I thought, I am going
to fill this child's life up with love
and hope and understanding. My husband's
reaction was slightly different. HE
WALKED AROUND GOING, "WOOHOO!
[screaming]
MY SOLDIERS WORKED."
It's not his.
Oh, the fuss he made when he found out I
was cheating on him.
Only child can't share.
My husband's English. He's from
Nottingham. And a lot of people ask me
if if my husband's Iranian. I go, "Well,
he's not. He's English, but he's
planning to convert.
His family are absolutely lovely." And
when they first met me, they kept going,
"Well, Shappie so exotic. She's so
exotic." Which means foreign, but not in
a way that we hate.
>> I think often a lot of people don't
realize there's an actual person behind
somebody's disability. And I experienced
this right firsthand when I got lost in
a park in Glasgow.
I came off the path. I I was in the
bushes
like looking like a like proper creepy
weirdo and
I heard this guy aggressively running
over at me shouting, "Oh,
you." [groaning]
And I turned to face him and he stopped
dead in his tracks went, "Oh, sorry,
pal. Didn't see the stick. [snorts]
Thought you were a pest."
You do know that's a pig guy.
Yes.
People only see my disability. I should
see how much I can get away with. Do you
know what I mean? Like how much of a of
a blind wronging can I be?
Just go to a supermarket, blatantly
shoplift a coat.
I get busted trying to leave through the
plate glass window again.
Security guard. Excuse me, sir. Is that
your coat? Yes. Do you mind taking the
security tag off it?
Certainly, sir. Can I just see your
receipt? Hey, big innocent face. Hand
him a blank bit of bog roll.
I bet he's not got the heart to say
anything above him. That's fine. Have a
nice day.
But I still maintain though it is it is
an excellent time to to to be disabled.
In fact, now in some areas, hey, too
good
to the point I' I'd like to finish this
evening by asking you lovely people of
of the Apollo a favor.
Could you please
stop modifying sport
so I can take part?
It's now getting harder and harder to
moan about being excluded.
>> [laughter]
>> But I am always been made to feel so
very welcome.
Not everything has to be accessible.
There's a message.
And being blind is a brilliant reason
not to have to do something.
Cuz this guy, this guy asked me if I
wanted to take part in a game of
football.
You cheeky bastard.
Oh, I'm going to guilt trip you, my
friend. I'd love to take part in a game
of football. Yes, but I just don't think
the blind man's that welcome in the
hallowed turf.
Not realizing
blind football.
It's an established sport.
What sick prick
came up with that?
22 blind lads running like [\h__\h] at each
other.
They're trying to kick a ball with a
bell in it.
Guys, that's not accessible. That's a
blood sport.
And who goes to see it?
[applause]
But I did. I did. I played my part. I
took part in one game.
Yeah, they put me in goals.
But I learned one thing
in flight. A ball with a bell in it is
silent.
But I think right I think women should
just let it out. It's a big day in a
girl's life when she can freely let rip
in front of her bloke.
It is I THINK WOMEN SHOULD BE HAVING I
FARTED IN FRONT OF my boyfriend for the
first time parties.
I do. I think THEY SHOULD BE RINGING UP
THEIR MOMS JUST GOING, "MOM, I've got
something to tell you." Oh, darling,
what is it? What is it? What is it? What
is it? I just did a fart in front of
Tom. OH, DARLING, THAT'S WONDERFUL NEWS.
Wonderful news. And what did he say? He
didn't say anything. He just laughed and
farted back.
My little girl's all grown [laughter]
up. Meanwhile, dad will be in the
background just going, "Women are
farting far too early in front of their
boyfriends these days." It was 18 months
before your mother even trumped in my
direction.
six months before she'd take a dump in
the house when I was around.
And also, I tell you something else, we
pretend as well. We keep the old uh the
lady garden quite tidy. Us girls, don't
we? In the early stages, we will do
little tricks with it. Look, it's a
strip. It's a Brazilian. Oh, look, I put
hair on it. It's a Mexican. Like, we do
[applause] we do all that in the early
stages and then after about a year, it
looks like the back of the wardrobe that
leads TO NA.
WELL, IF he wants it, HE'S GOING TO HAVE
TO WORK FOR IT.
People say to me, Andy, you could try
meeting people in a nightclub. You
You'll never meet anyone good in a
nightclub because the nightclub
environment is designed to have us make
bad decisions. It is cuz it's dark. You
can't see. You can't hear. You know
what? If nightclubs want to be
responsible, what they should do to help
us out is just before the exit, they
should have a brightly lit room where
you can check out the person you're
leaving with.
Yes, they should. They should CALL IT
THE HAVE A SODEN WORD WITH YOURSELF
LOUNGE.
And you'd literally get women in there
just going, "Oh my GOD, YOU'RE WEARING A
FLEECE. I couldn't tell cuz it's so dark
in there." Okay, nice to meet you.
[applause]
But listen, if you meet somebody online,
all I'm going to say is there's some
safety things to take into
consideration. Now, I met somebody
through Twitter, just the once. I'll
never do it again. And it was the most
irresponsible thing I think I've ever
done. And I spoke to a friend about it
before we met up. And I said, "Listen,
I've met this guy and we seem to really
like each other." And we're talking
about meeting up. What do you reckon?
Should I meet him? And before my mate
even had a chance to say anything, I
said, "You know what? I am going to meet
this guy. You know why? Cuz life's too
short." short. And my mate just read,
"Yeah, you're going to find out how
short."
And my mom says, she says, "Look, if you
go on these dates, make sure you meet in
a public place." Okay? And I'm just
going to add something to that. Public
place, brill
toilet.
Don't meet in a Never meet in a public
toilet. No good can come of it. Unless
it's, you know, them space age toilets
that they have outside where you put the
money in, press the button, and then the
door opens. You know why? Cuz you can
pretend it's blind date.
How cool is that? You just put the money
and press the button. [laughter]
And if you don't like it, JUST PRESS THE
BUTTON really quickly. [laughter]
I don't know why like young couples, new
couples have got this obsession with
finding out how many people someone's
been out with from before. Like how many
previous partners? How many previous
partners? This is a lose-lose situation,
right? And if any of you have ever had
that conversation or you think it's ever
going to come up, this is what I say.
This is what you should say. Okay? Just
say to the person that's asked you, you
want to know how many previous partners,
okay, I'll tell you from the beginning.
All right? 1 2 3 4 You. Six. Seven.
[applause]
One of the major good things that's come
out of it is how we've embraced new
technology, isn't it? Cuz it's just
unbelievable. Who knew what Zoom was two
years ago? None of us. Like last week, I
had to do a speed awareness course
online. Now, you should be doing that on
something called Zoom. But that's the
WORLD WE'RE IN NOW. It's the world we're
in. I've got a phone that can recognize
my face. That already makes it better
than my nan. Come on.
I embrace new technology. I do because
could you imagine if this pandemic had
happened like 30 years ago? No internet,
no Zoom, no Pornhub. I don't know why I
looked at you, sir, but I did.
Cuz I think we've forgotten here in
2021. We've forgotten what really being
bored feels like. Like proper proper
bored. My friend's little boy said the
other day he gets bored waiting for an
app to load. [\h__\h] off, mate.
That is not boredom, IS IT? I'M TALKING
SUNDAY afternoon in the 80s. That was
boredom when it was raining. You'd read
every book in the house. I grew up in
Maidstone. That's a Mills and boon and
an Argos catalog.
Your mom's watching something black and
white on the only telly in the house. So
you listen to your Waltman for a bit,
but the batteries are dying. So
Madonna's like a virgin. Sounds like
Barry White singing it.
You can't go and buy more batteries, can
you? You can't. Cuz all the shops are
shut. And I mean, all the shops are
shut. Even the petrol stations are shut.
And then when you think your day can't
get any more tedious, your daddy go,
"Get in the car, everyone. We're going
to go and visit someone."
That's what we do, isn't it? ON A SUNDAY
afternoon in the 80s, we would visit
people for no reason other than to ruin
their day.
Do you know what? Young people don't
believe this. When you tell them, "We
never told them we were coming."
Could you imagine doing that to someone
today? They'd be livid, wouldn't they?
We used to spend every Sunday with
people wishing that they'd hoovered and
we'd [\h__\h] off, didn't we? I'M QUITE
HONORED. THE ONLY PEOPLE WHO PHONED
AHEAD IN the 1980s were the IRA. Fact.
[applause]
I wouldn't I wouldn't be a teenager now
though, would you? I wouldn't be a
teenager now. When I think of the things
I did when I was a teenager, the thought
of that being on the internet forever
makes me feel physically sick. It does.
The way they have to communicate with
each other is something I just can't
understand. You know, texting. I
couldn't write a text. I don't know what
to put in a birthday card.
When I was a teenager, if I wanted to
leave a sexy message for a boy, I'd have
to ring his landline and leave a message
with his mom.
Went to what, dear?
All over your watch.
Different times, isn't it? Different
time. There's a boy I fancied at school.
I couldn't text him to write him a note,
stick it in his school bag, and I make
him a mixtape.
Write him a poem. That's all we asked,
didn't we? I genuinely think a
14-year-old girl today, she would be
more freaked out if you sent her a poem
than if you sent her a picture of your
knob.
PO WOULD FREAK OUT MORE. SHE'D BE WITH
HER FRIENDS GOING, "I MEAN, it was like
a song, but it wasn't a song."
And there was no [\h__\h] in it.
Not even a bollock. No, different
crimes, you know. Apparently, young
people today, they are most likely now
to have their very first sexual
experience online. By FaceTime or Skype.
They're not even in the same room. You
got one teenager in this house on their
phone and the other teenager in this
house on their phone and that's how
they're having their first sexual
experience. And I just think, do you
know what?
Getting fingered behind a caravan at a
fairground
is not ideal,
but at least I was getting some fresh
air.
My parents are disappointed I didn't get
married cuz like I said, I'm Egyptian.
I'm in my 40s, so I was supposed to be
married 30 years ago. So, they're like,
"Tick tock.
When's this happening?" But they don't
understand dating. My parents didn't
date. They were in arranged marriage.
Uh, they met on the Bachelor season 3. I
think
they don't get that joke or anything I
do. But um
I was supposed to be a doctor or a
lawyer or an engineer, which is pretty
typical for Arabs actually. Like I went
to Palestine once to do comedy there
because that's what that region needs,
just dick jokes. So thought I'd help.
And after the show, there was a Q&A and
somebody in the audience was like, "Why
did you decide to become a comedian?"
And as a joke, I was like, "I wasn't
smart enough to be a doctor." But they
didn't get it. They were like, "Oh, I'm
sorry.
maybe if you study harder, you can do
it. I was like, yeah, definitely. This
is a lifelong dream. That's all right.
[laughter]
My dad thinks I'm his responsibility
until I'm my husband's responsibility.
But at no point am I to be my own
responsibility, right? Like the women in
my culture need to chaperone through
life. Like we just don't have the same
rights as the men. Because my dad wanted
to move from Cairo to America, so he
just moved. You're a man. Bye. Right. My
mom wanted to move from Cairo to America
and they were like, "Well, let's find
you a husband in America." And that's
how they met. Three of my aunts became
nuns.
That's a lot of nuns for one family. And
I was like, "Mom, why did all your
sisters become nuns?" She was like, "Cuz
they didn't want to get married." And
then she caught herself. She's like,
"Because they love God."
I was like, "No, I knew it. Face all
their options. Meet Samir. He doesn't
know how to do his own laundry and he
has hummus in his beard right now.
You can have sex with him every night or
meet God. The only thing you have to do
on your knees is pray. And they were
like,
"Yep, God. That's perfect. Thank you.
I love I love being in London because
it's so close to the rest of Europe. I
love to travel. I go to Paris. Tell my
American friends I'm going to Paris.
They get so excited for me. They're
like, "Oh my god, Perie. We love that
for you. We love Amaly. And and I tell
people here I'm going to Paris. You
don't give a [\h__\h] at all.
All you ever say when I say I'm going
there is, "Oh, cool. How are you getting
there? Are you taking the train?"
Oh, the train's so great. You're going
to love the train. Like cool. Every
time.
How you getting there? You taking the
train? Oh, the train is so great. Like,
so is Paris. Why can't I talk about
Paris? What? I'm going to go to cafes
and museums. I'm going to see Jim
Morrison's grave. And you're like,
that's cool. How are you getting home
though? You taking the train?
Train's so great. Like, it's a good
train. Relax.
It's good to vomit on. And
last time I was there, this Parisian man
walks right up to me. He was like, "You
have fire."
This is why I love the French. What a
thing to say to a stranger. You have
fire. Yeah, you're damn right. I have
fire, sir. Right. I'm a strong
independent woman. I'm a comedian. He
didn't know any of this, but he must
have just seen something in me, like my
aura, and he had to come up and be like,
"You have fire." Turns out he [snorts]
was just looking for a lighter.
>> Cable was the more middle class option.
Yes. No, we don't want a satellite dish
sticking out the side of our house. No,
thank you. I think it looks really quite
naff. Yeah. Whereas the working class,
the satellite dish was the key selling
point.
If you're paying £25 a month, you want
your neighbors to know
that you are better than them.
And we had Sky through a dish 1997. You
could be watching Old School Sky in the
living room, watching it on the main TV,
but you could also go upstairs to the
bedroom TVs, turn to a certain channel
and watch Sky in the bedroom, but only
what the person in the living room
was watching. I don't know the intrinsic
technical explanation as to why this
happened, but it just did.
Saturday nights, me and my dad. I'm on
the couch, he's in his chair, my mom's
in bed, my brother's out with his pals.
Just me and the old man watching match
of the day, watching the highlights. It
gets to the kind of shite games. And I
say, "Right, I think I'm I think I'm
going to go to bed, Dad.
Good night.
And he would continue the sherad and he
are you off to bed, son? Good night.
And there was that mutual father and
son. We both know what the plan is here.
I would I would casually exit the living
room nice and slowly. Good night. Hit
the hallway and race up the stairs.
Don't even consider looking in the
fridge. Eyes on the prize.
Upstairs. Bedroom TV switched on. Go to
number six. That's you see he's
watching. TVs are synchronized. Six.
We're in. He's in control.
A few minutes go by and he's still
watching match of the day. That's fine.
He must be giving it a few minutes. You
don't want to make it too obvious.
He's done this before.
Five minutes go by. He's still watching
match of the day. I'm thinking, come on,
stick to the plan. Andy,
I'm looking at the bottom left of the
screen, waiting for the numbers to get
typed in.
The numbers that could make or break the
evening's entertainment.
Give me your numbers, Andy. Come on.
Nine. That's a good start. Nine.
Could
not have hoped for a better start than a
nine there.
05 the 10-minute free view.
>> You're a dirty bastard, Dad. But I love
you.
[applause]
So, we've got some celebrities in as
always live at Apollo. Who have we got?
Who have we got? We've got the East
Enders cast. How we doing? East Enders
sitting right at the back. I don't mean
the extras. I mean the real people.
[applause]
They're trying to get Phil Mitchell. No.
Where is he? Is he up at He's up at
King's Cross dressed up as a a lady boy
trying to raise enough money to buy a
pot.
Don't you think it's crazy that Do you
understand the technology for us to hear
the pilot? I am actually utilizing it
right now.
This is the technology for us to hear
the pilot. I don't know why we cannot
hear. There's no other context where
it's acceptable for us not to hear a
person. Why are you muffling? If you
were looking for an old pair for your
kids and a person came over to your
house and said, "Hey man, what's your
experience with kids?" And then they
looked at you and went,
>> [applause]
>> like you need to get out of my house or
something.
[laughter]
Weird things happen in airplanes. Weird
things. Like crazy things. Bizarre
things. Like, how bizarre would it be
right now if someone walked in here and
started selling us watches and perfume?
Would that be the most bizarre thing?
But it happens all the time in
airplanes. No one's ever gone, "Huh,
this is crazy." This is an English
polite thing. Oh, I've already got one.
Yeah.
I'm not looking at the moment.
[laughter]
[clears throat] Not every airline should
be selling watches though. Like Ryan
Air, no business selling watches. You
need the watch, Ryan Air. Your flight's
7 hours late.
And also, WHY AM I buying a 400B watch
on a 11B flight?
This makes no sense.
[laughter]
>> Yeah, being London is cool. I like being
in London. One of my favorite things to
be in London. There's so much to do. I I
tried to buy a ticket online to watch
Wimbledon. Yeah, man. The Wimbledon
final. I was like, I'm excited. Went
online. It was £3,000.
I was like, what? £3,000?
Okay, I'm not saying I wouldn't pay
£3,000,
right? I'm not saying I would pay £3,000
for a for a Champions League
finals ticket.
But I'm not paying £3,000
for a sport where someone is going to
tell me, "Quiet, please."
Are you out of your mind? For £3,000,
there will be no quiet place.
For £3,000, I'm rubbing my nipples
center court.
Are you out of your mind?
Three, my brother. £3,000. £3,000. Oh,
it's a lot of money. £3,000, my brother.
£3,000
for £3,000. I should be able to whisper
some advice in Roger Fezer's ear.
£3,000. £3,000.
I should be able to walk into the court.
Sorry, Roger. Come on. Forearm. Let's
work on that. Come on.
Three. My brother. 3,000.
For three. For 3,000. I should be able
to punch a ball boy in the face.
For 3,00 3,000.
Could be walking across picking up a
ball up.
Upper cut him in the nose.
He was so confused. What was that for?
I'm like, "No, it's part of the package.
If you look carefully, I can kick you in
the balls."
[laughter]
I was such a fat kid. My mother used to
buy bathing suits with blow holes in
them. It was just But my I don't want to
go into my childhood here because it's
wrong. My parents hated me. Okay, we're
all going to hear the story, aren't we?
My parents hated me, too. My parent All
I ever heard, All I ever heard growing
UP IS, "WHY CAN'T YOU BE LIKE YOUR
COUSIN SHEILA? WHY CAN'T YOU BE LIKE
YOUR COUSIN SHEILA?" Sheila had died AT
BIRTH. THEY JUST hated me.
Hated me. THEY WHENEVER WE GO LIKE IN
FRONT OF A STREET, they take each parent
would take my hand, hold our hand, we're
crossing the street, and then they'd
swing me into the trap. And they used to
say, "Take candy from strangers." It is.
Ask the funny man in the raincoat, does
he own a van? It is.
No, I I had a very bad childhood. And
that's because, and I'm sure none of you
give a damn, but I was the only Jewish
kid, this is the absolute truth, growing
up in an all Catholic neighborhood. You
know what that the Irish people only
Jewish kid in a Catholic neighborhood.
You know what that's like? You were all
doing Hail Marys. I was doing Hail
Murray's. I mean, it was just me. No
Christmas tree.
No Christmas tree. Do you know what
that's like when you're the only kid
without a Christmas? Cuz everybody has
Christmas trees. And nowadays, it's
like, well, we do it for all faiths.
That's such [\h__\h] Yeah. We walk into
a into a uh an office building and
there's a Christmas tree and there's a
renora. [\h__\h] THE CHRISTMAS TREE
GOES UP UP [laughter] UP UP. It's like a
little shitty manora with two orange
lights that some angry Puerto Ricans lit
backwards. I mean, yes, Juan, YOU LIT
THOSE LIGHTS BACKWARD. [\h__\h] YOU. You
killed our Lord. I mean, it is just
So, I'm at the age where I figure screw
it. I'm going to have a Christmas tree.
I got the biggest Christmas tree in. I
got a twostory high Christmas tree. I
put everything you could think of on
that up up. Gorgeous, gorgeous,
gorgeous. On the bottom, I got the the
manger. I got the whole goddamn thing
going there. The wise men, the sheep.
The only thing is I had the baby, but
I'm Jewish. I got him a nanny. It was
just Oh, yes. And I redressed Mary.
She didn't look good in that stupid
thing over her head. Come on. I put her
in a Chanel suit,
Manola Blanx, and a Louis Vuitton
pocketbook. You're the mother of God.
Look it. It is just
[applause] Am I wrong?
If she had looked like that, she would
have gotten into the inn. Yes.
The point is it's about looks. Mary, she
looked good. She would have done better.
Mother Teresa.
Oh, don't give me Oh, Mother Teresa, if
she had looked better, she'd be a saint
by now. Was she a bow? Yes. Did she need
electrolysis? Let's talk to each other
here. Even lepers were throwing their
fingers at her. here
cuz it IS ALL ABOUT LOOKS. THIS IS MY
MESSAGE, Great Britain. This is my
message. Looks count. Education.
Looks count. I have no sex appeal. And
it has screwed me up for life. Peeping
toms. Look at my window. Pull down the
shade. YOU HAVE YOU HAVE NO IDEA. My
gynecologist examines me by telephone.
It is just
>> I was in Hollywood recently. on an
all-inclusive. We all love an
all-inclusive holiday, don't we? Oh, I
chips and gate for breakfast. Yes.
I always think it's amazing. I can
always identify where people are from on
an all-inclusive holiday. It's
fascinating for me. Like the Italians,
you can always tell the Italians because
they could put on a bag of rags and look
amazing. Then you can see the Germans
and they're quiet and they're the
reserved. And then there's us, the
British.
That's interesting, isn't it? Because we
all want to become pals of each other.
I've had a pen pal in walking for 25
years that I met in Lanzerothi, right?
But it was a really really interesting
for me because there's a way I can
always tell if someone is from the south
of England on holiday. And it it it's I
don't need to hear your accent. Nothing.
The way number one I will tell if you
are from the south of England is it will
be 9:00 at night. It's 28°.
The moon and the stars are out and you
come out wearing a wee jumper
because it gets a bit chilly.
It's 28°
the moon's out. I'm Scottish. I'm like
past the factor 50 hen.
I do not trust the moonburn. Get me the
factor 50.
Then there's another way I can always
tell someone is from the south of
England. You and I are on an
all-inclusive holiday. We can eat as
much as we want and they will go to the
bar and they will order a half pint.
No, you can't order a half pint in
Scotland.
Next time you visit Scotland, try and
order a half pint. That is one of the
most tense conversations you will ever
have.
About 3 months ago, I went to a bar in
my home city of Glasgow and I says to
the barman, "Can I have two pints of
lagger and a half pint of lagger?" And
he looked at me and he went, "What was
that?" I said, "It's two p." He went,
"No, no, no, just the last one."
I mean, it's just just a half paint of
lagger, mate.
Hold on. Come here. Tell him.
Just the last one. I mean, it's just a
half paint a lagger.
Is that for you?
It's for my pal.
Are they on antibiotics?
Are they pregnant?
Would they like a coloring book and
crayons with that?